来，先看看这个。
So, take a look at this.
这是欧洲最重要的高速公路之一，
It's one of Europe's most important highways
横贯瑞士全境。
running all the way across Switzerland.
它连接了德国和意大利边境，
It connects the German and Italian borders
在阿尔卑斯山脉中开辟出一条清晰的通道。
creating a clear route through the Alps.
这段旅程直到20世纪末才成为可能，
It's a journey that's only been possible since the late 20th century
而这一切都要归功于这条隧道——
and it's all thanks to this tunnel
每年有数百万人依赖它出行。
which millions of people rely on every year.
但如今它开始老化，不得不关闭进行维修。
But now it's starting to show its age and has to close for repairs.
如果没有某种替代方案，
Without some sort of replacement,
后果可能相当严重，整个地区都将陷入混乱。
the consequences could be severe and cause chaos right across this region.
正因如此，瑞士政府正在采用最前沿的技术建造第二条隧道，
Which is why the Swiss government is building a second tunnel
确保这条关键通道始终畅通。
to ensure this critical corridor remains open using cutting-edge techniques.
这个项目绝对不能失败，然而现在它正面临一个相当棘手的问题，
It's a project that simply cannot fail
让这台庞大的设备陷入了进退两难的局面。
and yet it's now having to overcome a pretty big problem
that's left this huge piece of equipment in a sticky situation.
让这台庞大的设备陷入了进退两难的局面。
想象一下，你正准备驾车穿越欧洲大陆，从北往南走。
Imagine you're about to take a drive across continental Europe from north to south.
假设你从阿姆斯特丹出发，目的地是罗马。
Let's say Amsterdam is your starting point and you're heading down to Rome.
很可能你的导航会带你穿过瑞士——
The chances are your satnav is going to take you through Switzerland
它就坐落在欧洲大陆的心脏地带。更重要的是，
which sits right in the heart of the mainland.
你很可能会被引导走这条特定的路：A2公路。
But more than that,
you're probably going to be directed down this road in particular,
你很可能会被引导走这条特定的路：A2公路。
the A2.
这是整个欧洲大陆极为重要的交通走廊，
It's a hugely important transport corridor for the entire continent
径直穿越阿尔卑斯山脉中部。
and it passes right through the middle of the Alps.
一旦它关闭，
If it were to close, thousands of drivers would have to find a detour
成千上万的司机就得在几乎无路可绕的地方寻找绕行路线。
in a place where they are very hard to come by.
他们要么被迫涌上其他本已拥挤的高速公路，
They'd either be forced onto other already busy highways
要么走这些狭窄的山口——其中有些冬天根本无法通行。
or one of these narrow passes,
some of which are unusable in the winter.
好在这种情况不太可能发生，
Fortunately, that's unlikely to happen
因为A2公路是世界上最令人叹为观止的隧道网络的一部分，而且不只是供汽车通行。
because the A2 is part of one of the most impressive tunnel networks in the world
and not just for cars.
这里有全长57公里的哥特哈德基础隧道，
You've got the 57 km Gotthard Base Tunnel
目前是世界上最长的铁路隧道——至少在里昂到都灵那条建成之前是这样。
which is currently the longest rail tunnel in the world,
at least until the one between Lyon and Turin finishes.
然后还有哥特哈德铁路隧道。
Then there's the Gotthard Tunnel.
不，这不是同一个东西——这是一条历史更悠久的隧道。
No, that's not just the same thing again, it's a much older one.
还有承载着A2公路的哥特哈德公路隧道。
And the Gotthard Road Tunnel which carries the A2.
为什么这些名字听起来都这么相似？
Why do they all sound so similar?
因为它们都是为了纪念圣哥特哈德——
Well, it's because
一位11世纪的德国主教。
all of them pay homage
to Saint Gotthard who you know is an 11th century German bishop.
简单来说，看这期视频你不用太纠结那些不同的名字。
Basically, for this video you've not got to get too hung up on all those different route names.
最重要的一点是：我们这里说的是公路隧道。
The main thing to remember is that here we're talking about the road tunnel.
它让A2公路在艾罗洛和格申嫩之间走地下近17公里，
It takes the A2 underground for almost 17 km between Airolo and Göschenen
从80年代就开始服役了。
and it's been doing so since the '80s.
开通之前，司机们得走哥特哈德山口——
Before its opening, drivers had to take the Gotthard Pass,
那条蜿蜒的山路早在1400年代就开始正式使用了。
a winding route
that was first used properly in the 1400s.
走山口通常要花1个半小时，而现在只需15分钟。
A journey that typically took 1 and 1/2 hours via the pass was cut to just 15 minutes.
建设历时7年，主要采用传统的钻爆法施工。
Construction took 7 years and was primarily done with conventional drill and blast.
如果你是B1M的老粉，肯定已经知道这是什么了。
Now, if you're a B1M fan, then you're going to know this already,
不过为了以防万一，简单说一下：就是在岩石上钻孔，填入炸药，
but just in case,
一声巨响，然后清除碎石。
it's where holes are drilled into rock, filled with explosives,
there's a huge bang,
一声巨响，然后清除碎石。
and the rubble is cleared away.
如此反复，循环往复。
Then you do that process again and again.
1980年竣工时，它成为世界上最长的公路隧道，这一头衔保持了20年。
Completing in 1980, it became the world's longest road tunnel, a title it held for 20 years.
如今它排名第七。
Today, it's the seventh longest.
然而进入2010年代后，这条关键通道已经需要全面翻新了。
However, by the 2010s,
this critical connection was in need of an overhaul.
整个结构开始显现出老化的迹象。
The structure was beginning to show its age.
于是在2012年，瑞士联邦委员会决定——
So, in 2012, the Swiss Federal Council decided
是的，你猜对了——再建一条新隧道。
it was time to, yep, you guessed it,
build yet another new tunnel.
并不是为了扩大通行能力，也不是为了完全取代现有隧道。
Not because it would boost capacity or replace the existing one entirely.
这条新通道的作用是接替现有隧道，
Instead, this additional crossing will take over from the current tunnel
让原隧道得以升级改造。改造完成后，
allowing it to be upgraded.
两条隧道将并肩运营。
Both tunnels will then operate side by side
once the original tube has been brought up to spec.
基本上，是为了达到安全标准，同时所有机电设施也需要翻新。我们不能把隧道
Basically, it's for the security standard and also all the electromechanical part have to be renovate. We cannot close the tunnel
关闭三四年。
for 3 4 years.
这就是为什么瑞士联邦决定建造一条新隧道——
That's why the Swiss Confederation decide to build a new tunnel,
第二条隧道，专门为了在不中断交通的情况下翻新第一条。
a second tunnel,
just to renovate the the first one without interrupt the the traffic.
提案提出四年后，瑞士民众在公投中批准了这一计划。
Four years after it was put forwards, the people of Switzerland gave their consent to the plan in a referendum.
又过了四年，准备工作正式启动，项目定于2030年完工。
Then once another 4 years had passed, preparation work began and the project was given a 2030 completion date.
好了，在我们继续之前——
Now, before we go any further,
如果你之前被那些不同的隧道名字搞得晕头转向，那你绝对想不到他们给这条新隧道起的名字：
if you were struggling with all those different tunnel names earlier on,
第二哥特哈德公路隧道。不过这个名字至少还算直白。
then you won't believe what they're calling this one,
the second Gotthard Road Tunnel, which at least makes sense.
新旧隧道之间有很多相似之处，这一点毫不令人意外。
Unsurprisingly, there are many similarities between the old and new tunnels.
它们长度完全相同，
They're exactly the same length
因为必须与夹在两者之间的原有服务隧道
because they have to run in parallel with the existing service tunnel
（即安全通道）平行延伸。
or safety gallery
that's placed in between them.
施工同样从两端同时推进，和1970年代一样。
And construction is taking place from both ends simultaneously, just like in the 1970s.
但工法自那以后已经大不一样了。
But the methods have moved on quite a bit since then.
所以这一次，大部分工作是用隧道掘进机（TBM）来完成的。
So, this time
most of the work is being done with tunnel boring machines.
不过在今天的视频继续之前，
Now, before we go any further
我得先暂停一下，因为我有一个终于可以公开的重大消息。
with today's video, we need to stop everything
because I have got some very big news
我得先暂停一下，因为我有一个终于可以公开的重大消息。
that I am finally allowed to share.
去年，企鹅兰登书屋问我有没有兴趣写一本书。
Last year, Penguin Random House asked me if I'd like to write a book.
我说好啊，然后我真的写了一本书，
I said yes, I've written a book,
就是这本。
and here it is.
书名叫《超级建造》——改变世界的10个超级建设项目。
It is called Megabuilds, 10 colossal construction projects that will change our world.
在过去10年里，
Over the last 10 years,
我近距离见证了这个星球上一些最不可思议的建设项目，
I have had a front row seat
on some of this planet's most incredible construction projects
它们全都在这本书里。
and they are all in here.
我把它们全部写了下来，
I've written about them,
比我以往任何时候都挖得更深，
I've gone deeper than I've ever gone before
比任何一期视频、任何一篇文章、任何一部长篇纪录片都要深入。
in any video, story or any kind of like long-form documentary.
这是幕后故事，
This is behind the scenes,
是近距离的亲历，有团队的故事，
it's up close and personal,
有人情味，有细致的工程解析，有我的个人经历，
it meets the teams,
还有一路上遇到的那些"糗事"——
it's the human stories, it's the engineering in detail,
it's my personal experiences
还有一路上遇到的那些"糗事"——
and some of the calamities I've had along the way
就是跟这些项目近距离打交道时发生的种种。
getting up close with these projects.
写这本书我真的非常享受。我的一些哥们
I have really enjoyed writing this. Some of my mates
就说："哦，不错嘛。但是——是谁帮你代笔的？"
have been like, "Oh, nice. Who Who ghost wrote that for you?"
没有人。我可请不起什么大牌代笔作家，
No one. I can't afford a fancy ghostwriter,
就是我自己写的。
me. I wrote this.
这本书的每一个字，
Every single word
都是从我脑子里流淌出来，敲进我的笔记本电脑，
of this has come from my head
再变成这本书的，
into my laptop
and then into this book,
全部都是为了让你们读得开心。
all for your reading pleasure.
说真的，我从没想过自己能写出一本书，
Guys, I never thought I could write a book,
但我做到了。当然我肯定是有偏见的，
but I have and obviously I'm biased,
但我自己读了读，感觉还真挺不错的。现在已经开放预购了，
but I actually kind of think it's quite good. It is available to pre-order now,
链接在下面。
the link is below.
预购非常非常重要。说真的，我未来的幸福感完全取决于你们有没有去预购
Pre-ordering is incredibly important. Basically, my entire future happiness depends on you pre-ordering
这本书。
this book.
所以，如果你喜欢B1M，
So guys, if you love the B1M,
喜欢这些故事，喜欢以通俗易懂的方式了解建造工程，
if you love these stories,
那就快去预购我的书《超级建造》吧。
if you love learning more about construction in a down-to-earth way that's easy to understand
and can be read by anyone,
那就快去预购我的书《超级建造》吧。
go and pre-order my book, Megabuilds, today.
这台TBM叫阿莱桑德拉，从北端掘进；
This TBM, Alessandra, is digging from the north
这台叫保利娜，从南端一路向上推进。
and this one, Paulina, has been coming up from the south.
两台机器的直径都超过12米。
Both have a diameter of more than 12 m.
经过大约两年的掘进，
After around 2 years of tunneling,
它们预计将在中间相遇——沿途穿越了完全不同类型的地层，
they're due to meet in the middle
having passed through completely different types of ground on the way
以及多个断层带，也就是所谓的剪切带。
as well as major fault zones, also known as shear zones.
这些区域的岩石破碎、强度较低，具有挤压特性。
These are areas of fractured weak rock with squeezing characteristics.
两台TBM都会在掘进数公里后遭遇这些区域，但它们不会直接钻穿——
Both TBMs are going to encounter them after they've bored for several kilometers, except they won't be drilling through them.
在这些路段，施工团队暂时切换回了传统工法。
For these sections,
construction teams have switched to the old conventional method, albeit temporarily.
马蒂集团是负责南侧施工的承包商之一，他们就是用这种方式来攻克一处特别棘手的地段的。
Marti Group, one of the contractors responsible for construction on the south side, has been doing this to get through a particularly difficult spot.
这个区域叫古奇剪切带。
This zone is called the Gütsch shear zone.
这是一个已知的剪切带，规模很大，在隧道5公里处有400米的破碎岩石。
It's a a known shear zone, very large,
400 m of faulted rock at 5 km in the tunnel.
大家都知道，以这个直径的TBM在这种挤压性岩层中作业几乎是不可能的，
Everybody knew that with a tunnel boring machine at this diameter,
因为它很可能会频繁卡机。
it would not be possible to go through this squeezing rock ground because
it would would get jammed very often probably.
尽管速度较慢，但在这类高压地层中，钻爆法被认为更安全。
Despite being slower, drill and blast is considered safer in areas of higher pressure like this.
这种方式能让施工更精准，
Doing it this way means they can be more precise,
可以立即用锚杆和喷射混凝土对岩石进行加固。
immediately stabilizing the rock with anchor bolts
and shotcrete.
简单说就是用一根大水管把混凝土喷涂到岩面上。
That's basically where you spray on concrete using a big hose.
这相当于给隧道打了一层初始衬砌，
It kind of acts as like an initial lining for the tunnel
之后再做防水处理，
before it's then waterproofed
再覆上更多的混凝土。
and covered with yet more concrete.
使用TBM时，隧道用预制管片衬砌，由同一台机器安装完成。
When using a TBM, the tunnel is lined with precast segments that are installed using the same machine.
穿越主要断层带的那些路段，其实是最早开挖的区域之一。
Those sections through the main fault zones were actually among the first to be excavated.
在主隧道开工之前，
A pair of access tunnels were built prior to the main one
先用一组更小的TBM建造了一对辅助隧道。
using a smaller set of TBMs.
这让施工人员得以提前进入，
That allowed construction crews to get inside early
在大型机械到来之前先把难度较大的部分处理好——
and tackle the more difficult parts
before the bigger machines arrived
之后再正式开始。
later.
从那时起，我们就能对这段挤压性地层进行全断面开挖，始终确保整个隧道段得到加固，
From there, we could start with a full face excavation through this squeezing ground
并维持必要的安全措施。
so that it was always possible to to secure entire section of the tunnel
and to maintain the right security measures.
不过，在任何主体掘进工作开始之前，
Before any of the main tunneling could happen though,
南北两端洞口的准备工作就花了好几年，确保TBM进场时一切就绪。
years were spent preparing the north and south portals
so they were ready for the TBMs.
那意味着还要进行更多的钻爆作业。
And that meant more drilling and blasting.
支持施工的配套区域也需要建设。
The areas that support the construction work also had to be built.
在格申嫩，人们凿出了一组地下洞室，
Up in Göschenen, a set of caverns were carved out
隧道衬砌所用的混凝土就在那里生产。
and that's where the concrete's being made for the tunnel lining.
选择在地下进行，是因为地面上的作业空间实在有限。
It's being done below ground because out in the open air, there isn't much space to work with.
我们还需要物资管理和混凝土生产的全套后勤保障。
We need all also the logistic for material management for concrete production.
地面空间非常非常有限，所以部分设施不得不建在地下。
We have very very small surface
and that's why part of the installation will be done underground.
比如北侧的混凝土生产，全部都在地下进行。
For example, the concrete production on the north side, it's all underground.
这些设施建在山体内部
There's also another more dramatic reason why these facilities
还有另一个更直观的原因：这一带很容易发生雪崩。
are set into the mountain.
It's because this whole area is prone to avalanches.
洞室附近有一处大型临时堆料场，开挖出的材料先存放在这里，
Close to these caverns is a large spot where the excavated material is temporarily stored
之后几乎全部会被再次利用。关于这一点，稍后再详细说。
before almost all of it is reused. More on that in a bit.
与此同时，在艾罗洛，由于雪崩威胁较小、作业空间也更充裕，
Meanwhile, in Airolo, because there's less of an avalanche threat here
混凝土和管片的生产都在露天进行。
and more space to work with, the concrete and segment manufacturing is happening outside.
到2025年2月，一切就绪，两台TBM正式开始掘进。
By February 2025, everything was set for the TBMs to start digging,
头几个月，进展顺利。
and so off they went.
And for the first few months,
头几个月，进展顺利。
all was well.
直到6月，保利娜遭遇了严重麻烦。
Until June, when Paulina found herself in quite a bit of trouble.
它才推进了不到200米，就遭遇了
She traveled less than 200 m,
远比预期更早出现的严峻地质挑战。
but was already experiencing serious geological challenges
much sooner than expected.
机器被迫停机——这在此类项目中绝对是迫不得已的最后手段。
The machine was forced to stop, which is an absolute last resort on projects like this.
而一旦停机，它就卡住了。
And in stopping, it then became stuck.
[笑声] 保利娜撞上了一片高度破碎的松散岩石和空洞区——
[snorts]
正是TBM最怕遇到的那种地层。
Paulina had hit an area of highly fractured loose rock
and cavities,
正是TBM最怕遇到的那种地层。
exactly the kind of ground that TBMs absolutely hate.
这导致隧道掌子面——也就是正在开挖的前端——
That caused the face of the tunnel,
发生了坍塌。
the part that's at the front being excavated,
to collapse.
现在的情况是，刀盘被卡死了。
The situation is that the cutter head is blocked.
机器的扭矩不足以让它转动。
The torque of the machine is not enough to turn it.
我们必须从前方解除卡阻，
We have to liberate it from the front
才能让它重新转动，钻穿这段困难地层。
so that it can can turn again
and bore its way through this difficult zone.
他们的方案是从已建成的辅助隧道
They're doing this by digging an extra access tunnel
分叉出一条额外的进场通道。
shooting off
from the one that's already been built
分叉出一条额外的进场通道。
into the fault zone.
这样就能绕到TBM前方，从那里往回挖，
It'll enable them
把机器解救出来——
to get in front of the TBM and dig back towards it
so it can be freed
预计在2026年春季完成。
sometime in the spring of 2026.
即便如此，这也是一次代价高昂的挫折。
Even so, it's an expensive setback.
想猜猜要多少钱？告诉你吧，
Want to guess how much?
Well,
大约2000万瑞士法郎，折合约2000万美元，
around 20 million Swiss francs or 20 million US dollars
被追加到了总造价中——
has been added to the overall cost,
目前总造价略超20亿法郎，约合27亿美元。
which stands at just over 2 billion francs.
That's about 2.7 billion US dollars.
这也导致工期延误了数月，
It's resulted in months of extra work as well,
不过他们仍在争取按原定完工日期交付。
although they're still aiming for the same completion date.
一些原本安排在后期完成的工作被提前，这500米的问题地段现在将改用钻爆法处理。
Tasks that were due to be completed later on have been brought forward,
施工团队将每天三班倒、每周七天
and this 500-m problem zone is now going to be done with drill and blast instead.
Teams are going to work three shifts 7 days a week
施工团队将每天三班倒、每周七天
全力追赶进度。
to get things back on track.
所以，只要不再出什么差错，
So, as long as there are no further slip-ups,
这两台庞然大物应该能如期在2027年胜利会师。
these giant machines
should be able to make their rendezvous
这两台庞然大物应该能如期在2027年胜利会师。
in 2027 as planned.
我想大家都会好奇：他们事先对这片棘手地带
I guess the question is,
了解多少？
how much did they know about this tricky area beforehand?
如果他们已经有所了解，
And if they knew a bit about it,
为什么一开始不直接采用传统工法呢？
why didn't they just go with the conventional method right from the beginning?
根据瑞士联邦公路局发布的新闻稿，
Well, according to a press release
南侧的复杂地质条件是可以预见的，所选方案本身也存在一定风险。
from the Swiss Federal Roads Office,
the challenging geology on the southern side was predicted,
南侧的复杂地质条件是可以预见的，所选方案本身也存在一定风险。
and there were risks involved with the method chosen.
换句话说，他们知道这里有问题，
In other words, they knew it was there,
只是实际情况比预想的更险峻，位置也略有偏差。
but it turned out to be more hazardous
and positioned slightly differently to what they thought.
地质数据并不匮乏，
There was no shortage of geological data, either,
大部分来自第一条隧道当初的勘测分析。
as most of it was taken from the original analysis for the first tunnel.
显然，团队现在不得不承担这次冒险的后果。
Clearly, the team is now having to deal with the consequences
但你要明白，这种判断本来就很难做到万无一失。
of this gamble,
but you've got to realize
但你要明白，这种判断本来就很难做到万无一失。
that this is not a simple thing to get right.
要对这种地质条件作出正确的评估，是非常非常困难的。
It's very very difficult to make a a right evaluation of this geology.
大的断层带
The bigger fault zone,
还比较容易定位，
it was easy to situate,
但有些小的断层带却是大麻烦，因为很难搞清楚这些断层带究竟在哪里。
but there
are some smaller fault zone there are a big problem because
但有些小的断层带却是大麻烦，因为很难搞清楚这些断层带究竟在哪里。
it's not easy to understand where are these fault zone.
这些断层带对TBM究竟会造成什么影响，也很难判断。
What the impact to the TBM this fault zone could have.
就连原来那条隧道当年也遇到了不少麻烦，
Even the original tunnel had its share of complications,
我们在世界其他地方也见过类似情况，
and we've seen similar instance in the past
比如印度和澳大利亚，而且后果更为严重。
in other parts of the world
like India and Australia
比如印度和澳大利亚，而且后果更为严重。
with even more serious outcomes.
从第一条管道和安全通道用传统工法施工的经验来看，
It was known from the building of the first tube and the safety gallery
那里本就存在大量问题。
with conventional methods
to have have a lot of problems going through there.
当时有一段不得不重建，就是因为地层的挤压条件。
They had to rebuild part of it because of a squeezing ground conditions.
地质条件在隧道工程中永远是挑战。
Geology is always challenging in tunneling.
你以为自己已经掌握了全部情况，意外还是会来。
You think you know everything about it,
there is still surprises.
顺带说明一下，两台TBM在最终都到达中间位置时，当然不会真的互相接触——
Now, we should clarify
那场面可就热闹了，
that obviously the TBMs won't actually physically touch each other
when they both eventually get to the middle.
那场面可就热闹了，
It could be quite messy
如果真撞上了的话。
if they did.
实际上，它们会在稍早的位置停下来，
In fact, they're going to stop just before that point
届时就会被拆解移出。
when it'll be time
to dismantle and remove them.
我们还需要解释一下这两台TBM的尺寸。
We should also explain something about the size of those TBMs.
你可能会好奇，为什么它们需要那么大，
You might be wondering
why they need to be so large
毕竟这里通过的最大车辆是卡车，
when the biggest of things that's going to travel through here
顶多也就4米高。
is trucks,
and they're only about 4 m high at most.
嗯，隧道衬砌大约会占去半米的厚度，
Well, the tunnel linings add around half a meter of thickness,
但更关键的因素是道路上下方的空间布置。
but it's more to do with what's going above and below the road.
上方要留出通风空间，
On top, there's going to be space for ventilation,
下方则会设置一组服务管沟。
and underneath there'll be a set of service ducts.
其中一条用来铺设隧道维护所需的各类管线，这不足为奇。
One's going to carry all the utilities for maintaining the tunnel, which is hardly a surprise.
但另一条将铺设高压输电线路。
But the other is going to have high-voltage power lines running through it.
这在欧洲其他地方还没有先例，
That hasn't been done anywhere else in Europe,
它将取代目前架设在哥特哈德山口大型铁塔上的那条输电线——那些铁塔可真不怎么好看。
and it's going to replace the line
that's now spread over the Gotthard Pass on big pylons,
它将取代目前架设在哥特哈德山口大型铁塔上的那条输电线——那些铁塔可真不怎么好看。
which isn't much to look at.
还有一个巧妙的设计，就是对开挖材料的处理方式——
Another clever idea is what they're doing with the excavated material,
总量接近750万吨。
which amounts
to almost 7 and 1/2 million tons overall.
其中约四分之一会重新用于本项目的混凝土配制，
Around a quarter of the stuff is going back into the concrete mix
以及原有隧道的修复工程。
for the same projects,
as well as the restoration of the old tunnel.
另外四分之一将用于道路铺设。
A further quarter is going to be used for road surfaces.
剩余的一半将被运往琉森湖——
The remaining half is going to be sent back to Lake Lucerne,
大约在格申嫩以北50公里处。
about 50 km north of Göschenen.
在那里，这些材料将用于营造浅水区域，
There, it's going to be used to make shallow water zones,
为动植物创造新的栖息地。
creating new habitats for plants and animals.
听起来很棒，但让我们回到之前的话题。
It sounds great, but let's get back to the earlier point for a second.
我们之前提到，建造第二条隧道并不会提升通行能力，
We said before that adding this second tunnel
这听起来可能有点奇怪。
won't boost capacity,
which might sound a bit strange.
虽然交通流量将分散在两条管道中，
Although traffic is going to be split across two tubes instead of one,
但这并不意味着通过这里的车辆总量会增加一倍。
it doesn't
mean there's going to be twice as much traffic coming through here.
实际上，将会是两个方向各走一条隧道，
Instead, there's going to be one tunnel for each direction,
这比现在的情况要好——目前两个方向的车辆在同一条相当狭窄的空间里
which is better than things are now,
对向而行。
where cars pass each other head-on
in the same quite small space.
但在新隧道里，车辆仍将单向行驶，
But in the new tunnels, the cars are still going to be traveling single file
另一条车道作为紧急停车带或应急通道使用。
with the other lane
reserved as a hard shoulder or an emergency lane.
这样做的目的是让隧道整体上更安全、更可靠——
The idea of that is to make the tunnels overall more safer
这一点很难反驳。
and more reliable,
which you can't really argue with.
而且，他们本来就不允许让这条路更繁忙。
And that's because they're not actually allowed to make this road any busier.
瑞士联邦宪法第84条明确规定，
Article 84 of the Swiss Federal Constitution states
阿尔卑斯地区交通通道的通行能力不得扩大。
that the capacity of transport routes in the Alpine region
may not be increased.
这意味着现有隧道附近经常出现的拥堵，
It means the congestion
在新隧道开通后可能并不会消失。
often seen around the existing tunnel
probably won't go away once the new one opens.
2025年，数公里长的堵车已经多次被报道。
In 2025, queues stretching for several kilometers were reported multiple times.
所以，有些人可能会觉得：如果新隧道不能解决堵车问题，
So, some might feel
那它究竟有什么意义？
this new tunnel won't actually make much of a difference
if it doesn't fix the traffic.
但也有人会说，这不只是关于交通的问题——
But others would argue it's about more than that,
更重要的是确保欧洲交通体系这条生命大动脉不会彻底停摆，
namely ensuring
this vital artery of Europe's transport system
更重要的是确保欧洲交通体系这条生命大动脉不会彻底停摆，
doesn't come to a complete standstill,
哪怕这台对整个项目至关重要的庞大机器，
even if this giant machine
眼下正在经历它自己的"停摆时刻"。
that's so crucial to its completion
is doing just that for the time being.
瑞士民众选择了这条第二隧道，我们有责任把它建好。
The Swiss population has choose for this second tunnel, and we have the responsibility to do it.
我认为这是瑞士目前最大的工程项目。
I think it's the biggest project now in Switzerland.
还有那些在工地上辛勤工作的人们，施工公司的每一位员工，
Also, the people
他们都以能参与这个项目为荣，我们也以能参与其中为荣。
they they work there, the construction company,
they are all proud
他们都以能参与这个项目为荣，我们也以能参与其中为荣。
to to work for for this project, and we are also proud to to work for this project.
一如既往，如果你喜欢这期视频，想获取更多来自这个权威建筑视频频道的内容，
As always, if you enjoyed this video
请务必订阅B1M。
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel
for construction, make sure you subscribe to the B1M.
请务必订阅B1M。